Hey, landlord!
（女性）ああああ大家さん
Don't poke it too much.
It'll smell really bad!
変にかき混ぜんと
すんごいにおいになるね
I know!
（大家）分かっとる
（大家）アア…ウジが湧いとるね
生ゴミでも放り込んだんかいな
Maggots are coming out...
Did someone throw away food?
アア…　大家さん何ね？あれ
Hey, landlord, what's that?
うん？
（女性）それそれ
That! That!
な…な…何よこれ！
What's this?
- "Curse Killing" Chapter -
Episode 01: OLDER BROTHER
When They Cry
Furimuita sono ushiro no
(shoumen dare)?
Kurayami ni tsume wo tatete
(yoru wo hikisaita).
Amadare wa chi no shizuku to
natte nodo wo tsutai ochiru.
Mou dokonimo kaeru
basho ga nai nara...
...kono yubi tomare
watashi no yubi ni.
Sono yubi goto tsuretette ageru.
Higurashi ga naku
akazu no mori e.
Atomodori wa mou dekinai.
（圭一(けいいち)）東京？
Tokyo?
（藍子(あいこ)）うん
お父さんの先生に当たる人がね
Your father's teacher
collapsed right before an event.
イベントの直前で倒れちゃったの
そのお手伝いで
東京へ行くことになって
It turns out I'm going
to Tokyo to help...
何日か
泊まり込みになりそうなのよ
...and it looks like
it'll be a few days.
お母さんがいない間自炊とか
しなくちゃいけないんだけど
While I'm gone,
you'll have to cook.
Keiichi, will you be all right?
圭一大丈夫？
（あくび）
（圭一）うん大丈夫
なんとかなるなんとか…
Yeah, I'll be fine.
It'll work out... Work out...
It's not going to work out!
（圭一）なんとか…
なるかー！
Your parents must
be having a hard time.
（ﾚﾅ）
圭一君のご両親って大変なんだね
そういうことじゃなくて
メシだよメシ
That's not the problem!
It's food, food!
親がいない間
どうすりゃいいんだよ！
What do I do while they're gone?
（沙都子(さとこ)）それなら覚悟を決めて
自炊なさればいいではありませんの
Then all you have to do is get
your act straight and cook.
Yeah, yeah! Food you make
yourself tastes really good.
そうそう　自分で作ったご飯って
とってもおいしいよ
Yeah, it's good to do sometimes.
（魅音(みおん)）ああ
たまにはそういう経験もいいね
（梨花(りか)）
お指を切ったりヤケドをしたりで
You might cut or burn
your fingers. Poor, poor you.
かわいそ かわいそなのです
フフッ…
ウ～ッ…しかたない
No choice.
やってやるぜ！
I'm going to do it!
いざ！
Here I go!
ホッ！ フンッ！ ハアッ！
オ～ッ！まるで料理の達人だ！
Just like a master chef!
…てマズイかも！
This might be bad.
What are you doing?
何をしてるでございますの？
早く火を止めなさいですわ！
Turn off the gas right now!
フゥ…
Wait, why are you in my house?
（圭一）…て
お前らなんで俺の家(うち)にいるんだ？
This is trespassing.
住居不法侵入だぞ
それを言うなら圭一さんなんか
放火の現行犯でございますのよ
If you're saying that, then you
were just caught for arson.
It was almost going
to be a huge fire.
もうちょっとで
大火事ではございませんの
えっ…やっぱり
あれって火事になりかけてたか？
I guess that was
really turning into a fire?
当たり前ですわ
Of course.
If Satoko and I hadn't come...
ボクと沙都子が来なかったら
...the fire would be flaring and
the fire trucks blaring by now.
今ごろボーボーで
消防車がウーウーなのです
す…すみませんでした
皆さんは命の恩人です
I-I'm sorry.
You're my saviors.
Honestly, you need
to be looked after.
まったく
世話が焼けるでございますわ
Y-Yes.
は…はい
I never expected to have
Satoko make my dinner.
まさか沙都子に晩メシを
作ってもらうことになるとは
圭一さんそんな所で
ボ～ッとしてる暇がございましたら
Keiichi-san, if you have time
to sit there doing nothing...
...then get the bowls
and chopsticks ready.
お茶碗(ちゃわん)とお箸の用意をなさいませ
私と梨花も食べますから
用意は３人分でございますわよ
Rika and I will be eating too,
so set the table for three.
Right, right.
Mi.
うん？
梨花ちゃんは上機嫌みたいだな
You seem to be in
a good mood, Rika-chan.
So different from
Satoko's bad mood.
沙都子の不機嫌とはえらい違いだ
Satoko isn't in a bad mood at all.
沙都子は全然不機嫌じゃないです
久しぶりにとても
楽しそうなのですよフフッ…
I haven't seen her having
fun like that in a while.
楽しそう？あれがか？
Having fun? She is?
It reminds me of when
Satoko was with her nii-nii.
沙都子はにーにーと
一緒だったころみたいです
うん？“にーにー”？
Nii-nii?
Nii-nii as in brother.
にーにーは“兄々(にーにー)”です
沙都子のお兄さんなのですよ
Satoko's older brother.
沙都子の兄？
（梨花）悟史(さとし)といいますです
Her brother?
His name is Satoshi.
Satoshi?
（圭一）悟史？
（梨花）悟史と
一緒にいるときの沙都子は―
When Satoko was with Satoshi,
she always had fun like this.
いつも こんなふうに
楽しそうだったのですよ
うん？楽しそう“だった”？
"Had fun"?
いま沙都子とは別居中なのか？
Do they live separately now?
Yes.
はい…
とても仲良しな兄妹(きょうだい)だったです
They were very close siblings.
今日圭一の所へ来たのだって
沙都子が言いだしたのですよ
Satoko was the one who
suggested we come by today.
沙都子が？
She did?
She couldn't leave you alone.
放っておけなかったのですよ
沙都子は
今でもしっかり者の妹なのです
She's a reliable
younger sister, even now.
ふ～ん…
Here you go.
（沙都子）はいどうぞ
（圭一）サンキュー
Thank you.
I'm going to eat!
じゃいただきま～す
オッ！
ご飯いい感じで炊き上がってるな
The rice is cooked well...
...and the side dishes
are well done too.
おかずもよくできてるよ
ホホホホッ…
褒められるのは光栄ですけど
I'm honored to be praised,
but it's not that great.
そんなに立派ではありませんのよ
The side dishes are store bought,
and I just opened a can for this.
おかずはお総菜屋さん
これは缶詰を開けただけですし…
No, this is a great dinner.
いやぁ これは立派な夕食だよ
ウフッ…まあ私にも
そこそこのお料理ができることが
Well, if you understand now that
even I can make decent food...
分かっていただけたのでしたら
それで十分ですわ
...then that's enough.
こうしてご飯を食べてると―
Eating dinner like this is like we're
eating with Satoshi, so it's fun.
悟史と一緒にご飯を
食べてるみたいで楽しいのです
I miss those days.
懐かしいですわね　一体今ごろ
どこでどうしているやら
I wonder where he is
and what he's doing.
Oh, Satoshi is my nii-nii.
ああ悟史っていうのは
私のにーにー…
あっ…じゃなくてえっと…
兄なのですのよ
No, I mean, um...
...my older brother.
ああそうなんだ？
Oh, I see.
（沙都子）
あんなに生活力のない人に―
It's a surprise that someone so
incapable of supporting himself...
家出なんて甲斐性(かいしょう)があったなんて
びっくりでございますけど
...could run away.
家出？
Run away?
まあそのうちひょっこり
帰ってくるに決まってますわ
Well, I bet he'll eventually
come back out of the blue.
俺沙都子のこと誤解してたよ
I've misjudged you.
I didn't think you were
such a strong person.
お前がこんなに
しっかり者だなんて思わなかった
I-I've always been strong.
私は最初からしっかり者でしてよ
I was just playing along
with you and fooling around.
圭一さんに合わせて
悪ふざけしてたにすぎませんわ
You're right. Good girl.
そうだな偉い偉いフフッ…
Are you really complimenting me?
I feel like I'm being teased...
ホントに褒めてますの？
なんだかバカにされてるような…
It's really a compliment.
Your cooking's really good.
ホントに褒めてる
沙都子の料理はかなりおいしい
Right, Rika-chan?
なっ？梨花ちゃん
み～　缶詰のイワシさんも
おいしいのですよ
Mi, the canned sardines
are really good too.
Jeez, Rika.
（沙都子）も～う梨花！
（梨花）み～
Mi!
それではまたあした
Well, till tomorrow.
ホントに送らなくていいのか？
真っ暗だぞ
You're sure you don't need
an escort? It's so dark...
ここからだったら
目をつむっても帰れますわ
I can get home from here
with my eyes closed.
There's nothing to be
afraid of if we're together.
２人そろっていれば
怖いものなしなのです
そうか
I see.
Be sure to brush
your teeth before bed.
寝る前には
ちゃ～んと歯を磨くんですのよ
Right, right.
どうしたの？梨花ちゃん
忘れ物か？
What's wrong, Rika-chan?
Forget something?
Today's Keiichi
scored 100 percent.
今日の圭一は100点満点でした
パチパチパチなのです
（圭一）えっ？
Clap, clap, clap.
I bet Satoko felt like nii-nii came
back and had a great time.
沙都子もきっとにーにーが
帰ってきたような気がして―
とても楽しかったと思いますです
From now on, I'd like you to play
along with her scolding sometimes.
たまに これからも
沙都子のお小言に―
つきあってあげてほしいのですよ
エヘッ…
早く帰ってくるといいなにーにー
I hope her nii-nii
comes back soon.
梨花！
Rika!
Good night.
おやすみなさいなのですフフッ…
Yeah, good night.
ああおやすみ
When They Cry
（藍子）ただいま
I'm back!
Welcome back.
おかえり
（電話のベル）
（藍子）圭一ごめんね　あっ…
Sorry, Keiichi.
Maebara residence.
（藍子）はい前原(まえばら)です　はい
Yes. Yes.
あっはい圭一ですか？
（圭一）うん？
Keiichi?
What's up? A club meeting?
（圭一）何だよ？部活か？
なに！じ…実戦？
絶対的な危機？ケンカか！
What? A-A match?
A total crisis? A fight?
Got it!
おう分かったすぐ加勢に行く
待ってろ沙都子！
I'm coming to back you up!
Wait for me, Satoko!
（自転車のベル）
（圭一）待て待て待て！
Wait, wait, wait!
前原圭一ただいま参上！
Keiichi Maebara has just arrived!
Um, can I ask you one thing?
（沙都子）あの…
ひとつ聞いてよろしいですの？
Why are you holding a golf club?
どうして
ゴルフクラブなんか持ってますの？
No way!
（圭一）ウソー！
（圭一）結局
大乱闘のケンカだと思っていたのは
What I thought was a big
fight was a baseball game...
...the Hinamizawa Fighters and
their old foes, the Okinomiya Titans.
雛見沢(ひなみざわ)ファイターズ対
宿敵興宮(おきのみや)タイタンズの―
野球の試合のことだった
Strike! Batter out!
（審判）
ストライク！バッターアウト
I totally misunderstood
the term "backup"...
（圭一）その雛見沢ファイターズに
助(すけ)っ人(と)として参加していた
我が部活メンバーの救援コールを
...and the club members were
helping the Hinamizawa Fighters.
俺は完全に勘違いしていたわけで
アハハッ…
（少年）いいぞ 沙都子！
（圭一）ハァ…
（少年）お肉焼けたぞ 肉
（圭一）まあ赤っ恥はかいたけど
Well, I made a fool of myself...
...but it turned out all right.
結果オーライってとこか
（入江(いりえ)）楽しそうですね
あんなにはしゃいで
Looks like they're having fun.
They're so energetic.
あっ…えっと…
Um...
I'm Irie.
入江です
入江診療所で医師をしております
I'm the doctor at Irie Clinic.
少年野球の
監督もやってますがねハハッ…
But I'm also a little
league baseball coach.
（入江）みんな
僕のことを監督って呼んでます
Everyone calls me coach.
Maebara-san, I'd be delighted
if you called me that too.
前原さんもそう呼んでくださると
うれしいです
Okay...
When you see
Satoko-chan's smile...
沙都子ちゃんの笑顔を見てると―
...doesn't it feel like
your heart is being cleansed?
なんだか
心が洗われる気がしません？
（圭一）そうですか？
Really?
…てあいつの笑顔じゃ皿１枚
ロクに洗えないと思いますけどね
I don't think you can even wash
a single plate well with her smile.
Coach, you seem to like Satoko.
監督は沙都子のことを
気に入ってるみたいですね
Yes, I like her.
I like her very much.
ええ気に入ってますよ大好きです
I'm planning to propose
to her when she grows older.
彼女がもっと大きくなったら
求婚しようと思ってます
あれ？ひょっとして前原さんも
沙都子ちゃんのこと狙っています？
Oh? Could it be that you're
also after Satoko-chan?
それは困りますね　私はもう
何年も前から狙ってるんですから
That'll be a problem since
I've pursued her for many years.
You're joking, right?
冗談でしょう？
（入江）うん？ハハハッ…
沙都子ちゃんの
お兄さんの悟史君も―
Her older brother, Satoshi-kun...
...used to actively play for
the Hinamizawa Fighters too.
以前雛見沢ファイターズで
活躍してたんですよ
I see.
（圭一）へえ…
（沙都子）フフフッ…
もっと活躍してほしかったんですが
転校してしまいましてね
I wanted him to play more,
but he transferred.
Transferred?
転校？
Misfortune happened.
不幸なことがあったんです
いろいろと
In various ways.
もう３年になります
ちょうど今ごろの時期でしたっけ
It's been three years.
It was around this time of year.
Satoko's parents
got into an accident.
沙都子ちゃんのご両親が
事故に遭われましてね
- Accident?
- Yes.
（圭一）事故？
（入江）ええ
They fell off a viewing
platform while on vacation.
旅先の展望台から転落されましてね
Then Satoko is...
じゃ沙都子って…
Yes, she's living
with Rika-san now.
ええ今は
梨花さんと一緒に生活しています
２人ともご両親がいなくて
心細い日もあったでしょうが
Since they're both parentless,
I bet they've had lonely times...
助け合いながら
生活しているようです
...but it seems they're helping
each other live their lives.
I've even seriously
thought about adopting her.
あの子を養子に迎えようと
本気で思ったこともあります
えっ？養子？
Adopting?
But I'm not married and have
no experience raising children.
ただ私は未婚でして
子育ての経験がありません
Unfortunately, it seems like
it's going to end as a dream.
残念ながら夢で終わりそうです
（入江）あの子には
いつまでも笑っていてほしいんです
I want her to keep
on smiling forever.
俺もそう思ってます
I feel the same way too.
仮にですよ沙都子を
養子にできたらどうします？
Hypothetically speaking,
if you could adopt her...
...what would you do?
う～んそうですね…
Let me see...
First, I'll make her
call me "master"...
（詩音(しおん)）“まず
私のことをご主人さまと呼ばせて”
...and train her
to be a serving maid.
“ご奉仕メイドに再教育します”
あっ…み…魅音！
いやお前は双子の詩音！
M-Mion!
No, you're her twin, Shion!
Why are you here?
どうしてこんな所に？
（詩音）それはですね
It's because I'm actually the
Hinamizawa Fighters' manager.
実は私が雛見沢ファイターズの
マネージャーだからなんです
Really? Then why
weren't you at the game?
ホントかよ？それなら
なんで試合にいなかったんだ？
I'm a manager,
but a phantom manager.
マネージャーはマネージャーでも
幽霊マネージャーですからテヘ！
There isn't much excitement
if you don't come to the games.
詩音ちゃんが来てくれないと
試合に華がないんです
Come and cheer us
on again like before.
また昔みたいに
応援に来てくれませんかね？
（詩音）
フフッ…まあ考えておきます
Well, I'll think about it.
I heard you played a major
role in the game, Kei-chan.
（詩音）聞きましたよ
圭ちゃん 試合で
大活躍したそうじゃないですか
ケッ…大活躍ねえ
Major role, huh?
If we're talking major roles,
it's Satoko with the home run.
大活躍ならホームランを
決めた沙都子のほうだろう
あいつ運動神経良かったんだな
I didn't know she was athletic.
悟史君とは大違いです
So different from Satoshi-kun.
きっと運動神経は
妹に全部取られちゃったんですね
The younger sister must've
taken all the athletic skills.
あっ…知ってんのか？兄貴のこと
You know about
her older brother?
You know too, Kei-chan?
圭ちゃんこそ知ってるんですか？
Yeah, I've never met him,
but I know a little.
ああ会ったことはないけど少しな
確か両親が亡くなったあと
転校したんだよな？
I believe after his parents passed
away, he transferred away.
転校？
（圭一）えっ？
Transferred?
Who...
誰が…
誰がそんなこと言ったんですか？
Who said such a thing?
Um, who...
いや誰って…何だよ？お前急に
What's the matter with
you all of a sudden?
すみません…でも圭ちゃん
I'm sorry...
But, Kei-chan...
よく知りもしないで悟史君のこと
転校とか言わないでください
If you don't know much about it...
...please don't say he transferred.
Please, I beg you.
本当にお願いします
Looks like you're on your
last plate to wash, Kei-chan.
圭ちゃんのプレートで
最後みたいですよ洗い物
お…おい
H-Hey.
By the way, it's still June, right?
（ﾚﾅ）
そういえばまだ６月なんだよね
今年は梅雨とかなしに
いきなり夏みたいだね
It's like summer came
suddenly with no rainy season.
I heard it'll be rainy
after the weekend.
週明け辺りからは
梅雨らしい天気だってよ
Hey, Satoko had
an older brother, right?
あのさ…
沙都子に兄貴っていたよな？
His name is Satoshi, right?
悟史って名前だっけ？
あれ？言わなかったかな？
転校しちゃったんだよ
Huh? I didn't tell you?
He transferred.
家出じゃないのかよ？
（ﾚﾅ）えっ？
He didn't run away?
ホントは
家出していなくなったんだろう？
He actually ran away
and went missing, right?
あっ…別に
２人を責めてるわけじゃないんだぜ
It's not like I'm trying
to accuse you of anything.
It's just...
ただその…
別に隠そうとかダマそうとか
そういうつもりじゃないんだ
It's not like we're trying to hide
something or deceive you.
Then why...
じゃどうして？
（ﾚﾅ）
ある日から家に帰ってこないの
He hasn't been back
home since one day.
どこへ行ったんだよ？
（ﾚﾅ）知らない
Where'd he go?
I don't know.
Satoshi didn't return
starting one day...
（魅音）ある日を境に
悟史は帰ってこなかった
We all searched the entire village,
and the police also helped out.
村中みんなで捜したし
警察も方々捜してくれたよ
Even with all that,
he couldn't be found...
それでも見つからなくて
家出じゃないかって話になってさ
...and there were rumors
he might have run away.
When the police checked...
警察の人が調べたらさ
悟史ってバイトとかでコツコツと
お金をためてたんだけど
...they found that he was saving
money from his part-time job...
...but he withdrew all of it
the day he went missing.
それをいなくなった日に全部
下ろしてたのが分かったんだよ
…で名古屋(なごや)駅で悟史に
よく似た人が目撃されたとかで
And someone saw a person who
looked like him at Nagoya station.
（ﾚﾅ）私はそんなのウソだと思う
悟史君は家出なんかじゃない
I think that's a lie.
Satoshi-kun didn't run away.
ちょっと待てよ
家出じゃないなら…
Wait a second.
If he didn't run away...
やめなよレナ
Stop it, Rena.
Because this is
Oyashiro-sama's curse.
（ﾚﾅ）だってこれは…
オヤシロさまのたたりだもの
Curse?
たたり？
Before Satoshi-kun
disappeared, he told me...
悟史君は
消える前私に教えてくれた
“誰かに見張られてる
あとをつけられてる”
...that he was being
watched, being followed.
“家の中までついてくる”
Even in his house.
“寝るとき枕元に立って
見下ろしてる”って教えてくれた
Before he slept,
he said it stood by his pillow...
...and looked down.
レナ
Rena.
That's undoubtedly a premonition
of Oyashiro-sama's curse.
（ﾚﾅ）それは間違いなく
オヤシロさまのたたりの前兆
I think he may have had the
desire somewhere in his heart...
きっと悟史君は心のどこかで
雛見沢を捨てて―
...to leave Hinamizawa
and run away.
逃げ出そうという気持ちが
あったんだと思う
それをオヤシロさまは許さなかった
（魅音）だからやめなって
Oyashiro-sama didn't allow that.
Just stop.
（ﾚﾅ）
オヤシロさまは雛見沢の守り神さま
Oyashiro-sama is
Hinamizawa's guardian god.
雛見沢を捨てて逃げ出そうと
する人を絶対に許さない
Those who leave Hinamizawa
and run away are never forgiven.
私はそれを謝った
でも悟史君は謝らなかった
I apologized for that.
But Satoshi-kun didn't.
So he was cursed
by Oyashiro-sama.
だからオヤシロさまのたたりに
遭ってしまった
オヤシロさまのたたり？
Oyashiro-sama's curse?
警察が家出だって決めつけたって
私は絶対に信じない！
Even if the police insisted he
ran away, I'll never believe that!
そんなの
たたりだと認めたくない人たちが
That's a lie selfishly made by
those who dismiss the curse...
勝手に決めただけのウソっぱち
...regardless of whether
they believe in it!
オヤシロさまのたたりは
信じようと信じまいと…
いいかげんにしろって
言ってるでしょう！
Didn't I tell you to quit it?
（魅音）あのさ圭ちゃん
Say, Kei-chan...
前に漫画貸すって約束したじゃない
良かったら寄ってく？
Didn't I promise to lend
you some manga?
Want to stop by?
Y-Yeah, I'll do that.
あ…ああそうするよ
そうなんだ？
じゃレナは先に帰ってるね
I see.
Then I'll go on ahead.
じゃあねレナまたあした
Later, Rena.
See you tomorrow.
うんまたあしたね
Don't worry too
much about just now.
さっきのあまり気にしないでね
I don't mind.
いや別に…
俺のほうが悪かったと思う
I think it was more my fault.
It's not like we're hiding
what happened to Satoshi.
（魅音）悟史の話は
別に隠してたわけじゃないんだよ
Um, it's something we don't
want to touch on too much.
その…あまり
触れないほうがいい話だからさ
Have you heard about
Oyashiro-sama's curse?
オヤシロさまのたたりの話
聞いたことある？
Just a little bit...
ほんの少しくらいなら
Satoshi's late parents...
悟史の死んだ親ってのがさ
ダムの誘致派でね
...were proponents of the dam.
えっ？雛見沢の人って村中で
ダムに反対してたんじゃないのか？
Didn't everyone in Hinamizawa
oppose the dam?
まあいろいろ事情があってね
Well there were
various circumstances.
ダム計画に反対する人ばかりでも
なかったんだけどさ
Not everyone
opposed the dam plan.
悟史の親ってのが
誘致派のリーダー格だったんだ
Satoshi's parents were leaders
of the dam proponents.
The government
supported the dam...
国はダム工事に伴って
多額の補償金を用意してたからね
...and prepared lots
of compensation money.
There were a lot who supported it
because they wanted the money.
そのお金が欲しくてダム計画に
賛成してた人たちも結構いたんだよ
運悪くその両親が
オヤシロさまを祀(まつ)るお祭りの日に
Unluckily, his parents...
...died in an accident during the
festival deifying Oyashiro-sama.
事故死しちゃったんだよね
…でオヤシロさまのたたりに―
That's why it's said they were
cursed by Oyashiro-sama.
遭ったんじゃないかってことに
なっちゃったわけ
So it's also said that
Satoshi's running away...
それで悟史が家出したのまで―
...was due to
Oyashiro-sama's curse.
オヤシロさまのたたりってことに
されちまったわけか
Well, something like that.
まあそんな感じ
For Satoko, talk of her parents'
deaths, Satoshi leaving home...
沙都子にとっては
両親の事故も悟史の家出も―
そして
オヤシロさまのたたりなんて話も
...and Oyashiro-sama's curse
are all unpleasant things.
愉快な話じゃないわけよ
Yeah...
だからさ私たちは沙都子の
家族の話には触れないことにしてる
So we try not to touch on
the subject of Satoko's family.
悟史のことは仮に聞かれても―
Even if we're
asked about Satoshi...
...we just lie that he transferred.
転校したって
ごまかすことにしてるんだ
I see...
そっか…今日は悪かったな
（魅音）うん…
Sorry about today.
See you tomorrow.
じゃまたあしたな
Oh, and also, could you
not mention Satoshi...
あっ…あとさ
沙都子にだけじゃなくレナの前でも
...in front of Satoko
and Rena too?
悟史の話は慎んでくれるかな？
（圭一）えっ？
分かったと思うけど
レナってどういうわけか―
I think you noticed,
but somehow Rena...
...doesn't take anything about
Oyashiro-sama's curse simply.
オヤシロさまのたたりの話だけは
笑い事では済まないんだよ
Ever since transferring.
転校してきたときから
あいつなんで
あんなにマジになるんだろう？
I wonder why she gets
so serious about it.
レナはね…あっこれナイショだよ
言ったら絶交だから
Rena was...
Oh, it's a secret. Say a word
and our friendship's over.
I won't.
言わねえよ
I heard Rena was cursed
by Oyashiro-sama once.
（魅音）レナはね…
オヤシロさまのたたりに
遭ったことあるんだって
She said so, and she believes it.
本人はそう言ってるし
そう信じてる
If you kid her,
she gets really upset.
茶化(ちゃか)すとかなり怒る
レナはふだんチャラけてるけど
She's normally easygoing,
but her anger's quite scary.
怒ると かなり怖い
（圭一）分かった
悟史の話はこれで終わりだ
I got it.
I won't talk about
Satoshi anymore.
To get my happiness,
I had done everything...
...but had done nothing
to be blamed and accused of.
The sound of footsteps
became louder every day.
Then I noticed the fact
there was no time.
I was a believer in life,
to be myself always.
And was asking
whether I would be alive.
Give me a reason
why not to adopt in this way.
Or judge me to be guilty
of so many incurable sins.
Tell me why or why not?
Complaining way too much.
Maybe I overlooked
something fatal for me.
Preview
What cannot be saved
is a single teardrop.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
すくいきれないのは１粒の涙
What cannot be stopped
is a cry of despair.
止められないのは
絶望への叫び
訪れるのは憎しみの連鎖
What is coming is
the chain of hatred.
When They Cry.
｢ひぐらしのなく頃に｣
"Curse Killing" Chapter,
Episode 2: BOND.
- "Curse Killing" Chapter -
Episode 02: BOND
"Curse Killing" Chapter,
Episode 2: BOND.
Can you believe it?
あなたは信じられますか？